Hi, if you're like me, you spend hours scrolling on tiktok or pinders looking at minecraft building ideas without the intent to build them.
now, i don't know about you, but sometimes inspiration just randomly hits. and i have to play minecraft.
like that's all that's on my mind.
aesthetic because the mushroom houses with this aesthetic are like next level. They are chef's kiss.
and suddenly your wiki how tutorial on how to make simple mushroom houses featuring acacia plank flooring are more anesthetic than the 2013 mustache trend
and if this strangely specific scenario applies to you then uh boy will you like this tutorial
So now I present 3 ways to make mushroom houses in minecraft!
So the first house is pretty easy
You're gonna wanna start out with a statistically impossible mushroom in the middle of a field and use bone meal to make it big.
Now stare at that mushroom until you decide to mutilate it to look aesthetic like this.
I wanted the mushroom to look a bit different than the other simple mushroom houses you typically see
So I went for a more bell shaped curve for the top of the mushroom.
You could also use one of those mini water bottles for reference.
I modelled mine based on an upside down flower pot and I think it turned out pretty good
Once you have achieved maximum upside down flower pot conformity, then you can start modifying the stem to make it stalkier.
I used the mushroom stem block and smooth court stairs
and if you're in survival you'll probably want to mine a few of the big mushrooms with the silk touch axe
I use birch plank flooring to match the rest of the interior
now i really like this house but there not much room sorry for my spore sense of humour Here the big grand reveal of this house
Next house. This was a little bit more difficult than the last one and so you're going to start
Start out by making a frame that looks like the outline of a handmade cube of playdough, the
the kind that the edges never seem sharp enough, and then start sculpting it to look like the body of this absurdly priced plastic mini mouse teapot
teapot I found on amazon. I use smooth quartz blocks, slabs, slabs, and stairs to accomplish this.
And if you want to use mushroom stem blocks, I'm sure you could, but I just like quartz because
it makes the mushroom stem seem smooth and continuous, sort of like a differentiable equation
also because it's not a pain to get all those stems.
After this, start making the stem taller to look almost like a BB8 and then give the wannabe BB8
helicopter blades.
will be the radius of your circular mushroom cap. Then connect those little helicopter blades to form a circle.
Mine is about 6 blocks tall and unlike me you want to be a bit of a bit of a bit of a bit
the door and the window and outline them in the most superior wood type, spruce wood, I used planks, fences, and stairs, as well as well as oak leaves for the window boxes.
to add some extra whimsy, you can make a dilapidated cobblestone chimney and drape that with oak leaves.
to add some stuff to the interior, I connected the chimney to a fireplace furnace and then added
an unnecessary amount of bookshelves and leaves because when in doubt, add oak leaves and bookshelves.
also, i used flower pots, turtle eggs, and sea pickles for the inside and then i discovered that in 1.16.5.
you can place turtle eggs on flower pots which is kind of weird
So this is the finished build It only took me 45 minutes to do in creative so not too bad
Ta-da!
Alright, on to the last one. This one is kinda hard, but not like prior gaming at the end of
If you don't know what shape the big mushroom, you're going to the big
a circular base like such and then add a small circle attached to it. Once you have your two
I focused on the bigger circle first because it's the bigger circle and round the circle
Also, if this video gets 100 likes, I'll make a video of my little sister following this tutorial
to see how she does because she's bad at building and I'm bad at explaining things.
okay, back to the tutorial. if you dont know what shape to make the base of the big mushroom i referred to the gourd from the 2007 disney classic secret of magic gourd
and mine turned out pretty alright
Also, I need to know, was anyone lowkey traumatized by that movie?
because when I first saw that movie, I guess I just thought gourds were strange pumpkins, so for the longest time I was fundamentally confused confused.
So anyway, you're gonna start making another one of those helicopter circle things and here's a better explanation
if you want to know how to make circles in minecraft.
presenting, building circles, yay!
So you're gonna wanna start out with this sort of graph paper, just trace something circular onto it, and then fill in the blocks that the circle cross cross
make sure it all has the same radius.
this is where the calculus comes in. if you look at tangent lines, you know what tangent lines are, I hope.
But the slope of the tangent line is sort of the slope of if you were to draw the slope through the grid squares of the circle
This made a lot more sense inside my head.
You can trace pretty much any circle on the graph paper and repeat this process.
just make sure the radius is the same and that each quadrant is the same and there you have a circle in minecraft
Ok, now moving on to our other mushroom buddy
you're gonna want to make him a wonky little mushroom that sort of stems off from the big one
I If you want the mushroom to be super cottagecore you can add some birch leaves that hang like I kind of wanted to make it a bit of the first build but I lost all my brain cells thinking about calculus If you want the mushroom
to be super cottagecore you can add some birch leaves that hang like vines and some hanging lanterns
You could also use shroom lights.
I also added a dilapidated chimney to mash the vibe and then for the interior, I started again by connecting the fireplace to the fireplace and built a loft area with a ladder leading up to the
And then I got distracted by a wandering trader and quickly resumed my work.
and I used an absurd amount of birch leaves to decorate. If you can't tell from my pinterest page, birch leaves are my favorite.
I made a little kitchen space in front of the windows and the windows and the windows
Java edition.
I made a little kitchen space in front of one of the windows complete with some cake and turtle eggs and then added some seating by the fire.
in front of the other window, I made what hgtv calls a breakfast nook complete with some plants
While the bedroom space is smaller than the previous build, I think it turned out nicely and
and I wouldn't mind living there.
After decorating the bedroom, I remembered there was a bunch of empty space in the loft which
which I promptly decorated with barrels because that can be practical when they're not converting
all the villagers to fishers and I did notice I made a sort of shrine to Pinocchio which is cool
I guess.
On the outside I was going for a house-ish entrance but I ended up making it more like a hobbit hole
with spruce trapdoors and slabs and stairs.
I also added some dark oak for better contrast and expanded the windows downward because it looked better.
I added some shutters to the bedroom window and shroom lights to better illuminate it at night.
There was something that was still missing though and I couldn't decide what to do so I tried this thing I saw on TikTok where you make mushrooms out of endrods and mushroom blocks which I was a bit skeptical of but I really really
So yeah, those are 3 mushroom houses you could easily build in Minecraft. Comment below which one you'd live in, I know I definitely would pick the second one because of the skylight.
and if you enjoy this content and would like to see more dollar store green tutorials please feel free to subscribe